Have you ever bumped into someone and their name just doesn't come to you?
你是否曾经意外撞见某人却想不起他们的名字？
Or, you walk into a room and suddenly can't recall why you're there?
或者，你走进一个房间却突然想不起自己为什么在那里？
Being forgetful can be really annoying, sometimes even embarrassing.
健忘可能真的很烦人，有时甚至令人尴尬。
But what if I told you that there are actually good reasons for our memories fading away?
但如果我告诉你，我们的记忆逐渐消逝其实是有充分理由的呢？
In a BBC interview, neuroscientist Charan Ranganath uses a hoarding analogy.
在一次BBC采访中，神经科学家查兰·兰加纳特使用了一个囤积的类比。
We don't tend to store everything we've ever owned in our house.
我们不会把曾经拥有的所有东西都储存在房子里。
Similarly, we don't need to store all our memories either.
同样，我们也不需要储存所有的记忆。
He says, "If we didn't forget anything, we'd be hoarding memories, and you'd never be able to find what you want, when you want it."
他说："如果我们什么都不忘记，我们就会囤积记忆，你就永远无法在你需要的时候找到你想要的东西。"
For example, you don't need to remember the hotel number weeks after you've left the hotel or memorise all the faces you pass on the street.
例如，你不需要在离开酒店几周后还记得酒店房间号，也不需要记住你在街上经过的所有面孔。
We also need to be able to forget things in order to update our memories with new information.
我们也需要能够遗忘事物，以便用新信息更新我们的记忆。
Imagine you get used to the same school timetable or work schedule for a whole year, but the next year, you have new procedures or routines.
想象一下，你一整年都习惯了同样的学校课程表或工作日程表，但第二年，你有了新的规程或日常活动。
Your brain needs to be flexible and forget irrelevant details in order to handle the new information.
你的大脑要灵活，并遗忘无关的细节，以便处理新信息。
Or, maybe it's been 10 years since you last saw a distant relative.
或者，也许你上一次见到一位远亲已经是十年前了。
It's likely their face has changed a lot since then, so that memory needs to be updated as well.
从那以后，他们的脸很可能发生了很大变化，所以那段记忆也需要更新。
And, if you've ever been convinced that you know a word, but it just doesn't pop into your head, you're not alone.
而且，如果你曾经确信自己知道一个词，但就是想不起来，你并不孤单。
This tip-of-the-tongue phenomenon may suggest that some things are not fully forgotten, just currently inaccessible.
这种话到嘴边却说不出来的现象可能表明，有些东西并没有被完全遗忘，只是暂时无法访问。
Those with a higher level of knowledge are more affected by this, according to studies such as 'Impact of knowledge and age on tip-of-the-tongue rates', because their brains have to sort through more information to find the word.
根据《知识和年龄对话到嘴边现象发生率的影响》等研究，知识水平较高的人受此影响更大，因为他们的大脑需要筛选更多信息才能找到那个词。
Memories are sometimes compared to a cliff: once they have crumbled, they are lost and cannot be retrieved.
记忆有时被比作悬崖：一旦崩塌，就永远失去，无法找回。
However, in their article 'Forgetfulness: Why your mind going blank can be a benefit', Sanjay Sarma and Luke Yoquinto write that forgetting, it seems, is "less like a cliff slowly collapsing into the sea, and more like a house deep in the woods that becomes harder and harder to find".
然而，桑杰·萨尔马和卢克·约昆托在他们的文章《健忘：为什么头脑空白可能是一件好事》中写道，遗忘似乎"不太像慢慢坍塌入海的悬崖，而更像是森林深处一座越来越难找到的房子"。